<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Sprites</title>
        <description>A blog about data visualization.</description>      
        <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://blog.spritesapp.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
            <item>
                <title>Introducing theme customizer</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introducing-theme-customizer&quot;&gt;Introducing theme customizer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re excited to share great news with you: we’ve just released a feature update that allows you to effortlessly create amazing personalized design themes in Sprites. Let’s quickly go through the new functionality to see it in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we’ve changed the way themes are laid out in the “Infographic settings” modal window. Now the drop-down list looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/create-theme-presentation-settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Infographic settings&quot; title=&quot;Infographic settings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s still a way for you to completely customize the given theme if you’re familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cascading_Style_Sheets&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt; but it’s now also possible to create a new one right in Sprites. This is done by selecting “Make your own” in the drop-down list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the selection is made, a new modal window appears:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/create-theme-step-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Create theme step 1&quot; title=&quot;Create theme step 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the first step of this simple 3-step wizard you’re prompted to pick an existing theme that you wish to customize (this can be one of the standard themes or even your own theme that you’ve uploaded earlier). When the selection is made, click “Next” to move to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/create-theme-step-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Create theme step 2&quot; title=&quot;Create theme step 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the second step you’re able customize previously selected theme by changing things like font family and color, accent colors, background color and image. You can now also specify a business logo that will be automatically displayed on every slide (something many of our users have been asking for).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a huge collection of various free fonts available to you via our Google Fonts integration. Start typing inside a text box to search for a particular font:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/create-theme-step-2-fonts.png&quot; alt=&quot;Create theme step 2 fonts&quot; title=&quot;Create theme step 2 fonts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also place your mouse pointer over the little “Text” icon on the right of each font to see how it looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/create-theme-step-2-font-preview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Create theme step 2 font preview&quot; title=&quot;Create theme step 2 font preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar “Preview” overlay is available for image fields (background image and business logo):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/create-theme-step-2-image-preview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Create theme step 2 image preview&quot; title=&quot;Create theme step 2 image preview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re satisfied with your customization, click “Next” to go to the last step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the third (and the last) step you can pick a new name for your theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/create-theme-step-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Create theme step 3&quot; title=&quot;Create theme step 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re done, click “Create theme” to generate a theme file that will be put into Sprites (the newly created theme will only be visible to you). After the theme is created, you’ll be redirected back to the “Infographic settings” modal with your new theme pre-selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick example of how you can take a standard Sprites theme and make something extremely pink out of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/create-theme-slide-example.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hello Kitty&quot; title=&quot;Hello Kitty&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’ll love the new theme customizer. Share your infographics with us by mentioning us on Facebook (&lt;a href=&quot;http://facebook.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;Sprites&lt;/a&gt;) or Twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;@spritesapp&lt;/a&gt;) as well as by adding a hashtag &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/spritesapp&quot;&gt;#spritesapp&lt;/a&gt; and we will make sure to spread the word about your story!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/04/19/introducing-theme-customizer.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/04/19/introducing-theme-customizer.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Presenter mode&amp;#58; Presenting your visual stories with ease</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;presenter-mode58-presenting-your-visual-stories-with-ease&quot;&gt;Presenter mode: Presenting your visual stories with ease&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presenting your Sprites infographics in front of a live audience just got so much better and easier! Let’s take a look at the brand new “Presenter” mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you bring up the “Publish” dialog, you will notice that there’s now a new tab called “Present”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/present-settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Present settings&quot; title=&quot;Present settings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can configure how your infographic looks and behaves when your intent is to present it on a large screen. For example, you may want to tweak default animations (by either minimizing them or turning them off completely). You can also tell Sprites to remind you to go fullscreen when infographic is about to be shown (you can always manually enter or exit fullscreen mode by pressing F11 key on your keyboard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re ready to present, hover over the “View &amp;amp; present” menu item at the top bar in the Editor and choose “Present”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/present-choice.png&quot; alt=&quot;Present choice&quot; title=&quot;Present choice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tip: You can load any Sprites infographic in a “Presenter” mode by appending “&lt;strong&gt;?presenter=1&lt;/strong&gt;” to the URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now, happy presenting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/03/03/presenter-mode-presenting-your-visual-stories-with-ease.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/03/03/presenter-mode-presenting-your-visual-stories-with-ease.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Import images from Dropbox, Google Drive and Flickr</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;import-images-from-dropbox-google-drive-and-flickr&quot;&gt;Import images from Dropbox, Google Drive and Flickr&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week we’ve been spending some time improving our “Image” element in order to give you more freedom and flexibility in bringing your images into Sprites. We’re excited to share some amazing results with you. Introducing a brand new &lt;strong&gt;media manager&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we have slightly changed the settings page of an “Image” element: when choosing “URL” as image source, you can now see a little “folder” icon next to image URL field:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/media-picker.png&quot; alt=&quot;Media picker&quot; title=&quot;Media picker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking on the “folder” icon brings up the media manager modal window:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/media-dialog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Media manager&quot; title=&quot;Media manager&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can choose image files from various sources. On the screenshot above you can see the files that I’ve uploaded earlier so it’s now super-easy to reuse images that you’ve already used elsewhere in Sprites (not necessarily on a given infographic). Just to remind you, Sprites supports the following image formats: JPG, PNG, GIF, BMP and SVG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also choose and image from your Google Drive or Dropbox folder by clicking on “Select from…” drop-down menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/media-selectfrom.png&quot; alt=&quot;Media from external source&quot; title=&quot;Media from external source&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last, but not least, you can now browse through public Flickr images by flipping the search filter from “Library” to “Flickr”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/media-flickr.png&quot; alt=&quot;Search Flickr&quot; title=&quot;Search Flickr&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions/comments/suggestions, don’t hesitate to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt; (or by using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt; on our website). Also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;like us&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;follow us&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter to get the latest product updates as well as tips and trick on making great visual content. We’ve also recently created an account on Instagram (&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;@spritesapp&lt;/a&gt;) where we you will be able to find everything around great visual design as well as follow our day-to-day life and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take care!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/02/18/import-images-from-dropbox-google-drive-and-flickr.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/02/18/import-images-from-dropbox-google-drive-and-flickr.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Introducing real-time collaboration in Sprites</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introducing-real-time-collaboration-in-sprites&quot;&gt;Introducing real-time collaboration in Sprites&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are super-excited to announce a new set of major features that we are making available as of today. These features are for teams and what they allow you to do is to collaborate on your Sprites infographics &lt;strong&gt;in real time&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at how to use the new functionality. Live collaboration in Sprites is based on the concept of sharing your infographic with other people. And in this case “sharing” means giving them “collaborator” access so that they could edit a specific infographic even if they didn’t create it originally. To share an infographic, click on your name in the top right corner of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com/edit&quot;&gt;editor&lt;/a&gt;. You will notice that the menu has been substantially improved:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/collab-user-menu.png&quot; alt=&quot;User menu&quot; title=&quot;User menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You now get two separate lists. First one (the top one) contains your own infographics and the second one (the bottom one) contains infographics that are currently shared with you. To share an infographic you need to invite collaborators which is done by clicking on “Edit” link under the “Collaborators” column. This brings up the following modal dialog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/collab-share.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sharing infographic&quot; title=&quot;Sharing infographic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add collaborators by typing their email addresses into the text box and clicking on “Add” button. When you’re done, click “Save” and Sprites will send out email invitations to the people you’ve specified. If the given person doesn’t have a Sprites account, he will be prompted to create one first. Note that all collaborators need to confirm their participation by clicking on a link from the email invitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, shared infographics behave exactly the same as the ones you’ve created yourself meaning that, as collaborator, you have nearly full control over them (changing elements, adding/removing slides, changing settings and so on). But the real power comes when you decide to work on your infographic as a team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’ve opened a shared infographic together with someone else, you’ll notice that you now have access to a team chat located at the bottom right corner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/collab-chat.png&quot; alt=&quot;Team chat&quot; title=&quot;Team chat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chat allows you to have quick, ad-hoc discussions about the work you’re currently performing, without even leaving Sprites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re multiple people editing the same infographic simultaneously, you’ll see each other’s updates in real time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/collab-live-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Real-time updates&quot; title=&quot;Real-time updates&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This instant feedback is not limited to just elements of your infographic but also applies to slides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/collab-live-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Real-time updates on slides&quot; title=&quot;Real-time updates on slides&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’ll love the new capabilities (all of which are available to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com/pricing&quot;&gt;Ultimate&lt;/a&gt; plan members)! As we mentioned, we’re extremely excited and proud of what we’ve achieved for all of you guys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions/comments/suggestions, don’t hesitate to contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#097;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt; (or by using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt; on our website). Also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;like us&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;follow us&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter to get the latest product updates as well as tips and trick on making great visual content. And last, but not least: we’re now on Instagram (&lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;@spritesapp&lt;/a&gt;) where we you will be able to find everything around great visual design as well as follow our day-to-day life and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/02/10/introducing-real-time-collaboration-in-sprites.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/02/10/introducing-real-time-collaboration-in-sprites.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Strong teams move faster</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;strong-teams-move-faster&quot;&gt;Strong teams move faster&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are continuing this year with some really exciting news: Sprites is happy to welcome our new family member - &lt;strong&gt;Daniela Alvarez&lt;/strong&gt; (Denny). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denny is joining Sprites as our own Chief Marketing Officer and a head of Business Development. With a keen eye for marketing and all things visual, she became the perfect candidate to bring Sprites, as a company, to new heights. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/team-denny.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Daniela Alvarez&quot; title=&quot;Daniela Alvarez&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A globe trotter who was born in USA, raised in Mexico, crazed-up in China and educated in Canada, Denny brings new ideas with focus and decision. An art and design enthusiast herself who decided to follow her true passion and pursue Business and Marketing after switching from an International Relations degree. This overly-chatty person is always here to help you so don’t hesitate to contact her anytime at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#100;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#046;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#118;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#122;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#100;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#097;&amp;#046;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#118;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#122;&amp;#064;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#112;&amp;#112;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites was created with the motive to enable everyone to create crisp visual content in the simplest and cleanest way. Denny comes in to spread every component of this vision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the family! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/02/04/strong-teams-move-faster.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/02/04/strong-teams-move-faster.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Exporting your infographic to PDF</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;exporting-your-infographic-to-pdf&quot;&gt;Exporting your infographic to PDF&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi folks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you had a great, refreshing holiday time. Today’s post is about yet another little (but awesome) feature we’ve introduced just a couple of days ago: it’s now possible to export your entire infographic to PDF file! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can access the new functionality by clicking on “Publish” in the main menu and then navigating to the “Download” (former “Download as image”) tab:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/download-pdf.png&quot; alt=&quot;Download as PDF&quot; title=&quot;Download as PDF&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, you now have a choice: you can either export a single slide to JPG image or you can do the same with the entire infographic when you choose “PDF” (thus, when “PDF” is chosen, you don’t need to specify which slide you’re interested in - the resulting PDF will have a slide from your infographic per page). The “Resolution” parameter corresponds to the image resolution when using “JPG” as output format and the PDF page size when using “PDF”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/01/10/exporting-your-infographic-to-pdf.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2015/01/10/exporting-your-infographic-to-pdf.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>New text editing capabilities</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;new-text-editing-capabilities&quot;&gt;New text editing capabilities&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, it’s officially a holiday season, we’re as always busy addressing your wishes and improving Sprites. Today’s little addition - new text editing capabilies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When editing the contents of a “Text” element, you can now click on a little “triple dot” icon on the toolbar and get additional text formatting options which include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Text justification (left, right, center, justify).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creation of ordered and unordered lists.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subscript and superscript formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a screenshot of a new toolbar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/text-options.png&quot; alt=&quot;Formatting options&quot; title=&quot;Formatting options&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same functionality is available when editing the contents of a callout or when editing tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, for the “Text” element you can now specify the maximum allowed width of a text block by using the slider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/max-text-width.png&quot; alt=&quot;Maximum text width&quot; title=&quot;Maximum text width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now! As usual, like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to get product updates, hints and tips on creating great-looking visual content!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great holidays!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/12/25/new-text-editing-capabilities.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/12/25/new-text-editing-capabilities.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Introducing slide templates</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introducing-slide-templates&quot;&gt;Introducing slide templates&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi guys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today marks the beginning of &lt;a href=&quot;http://websummit.net/&quot;&gt;Web Summit&lt;/a&gt; where our &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ziflex&quot;&gt;Tim Voronov&lt;/a&gt; is sharing our passion for elegant and beautiful visual stories with some of the conference attendees (if you’re over there, make sure to stop by the stand &lt;strong&gt;SCL125&lt;/strong&gt; to say “Hi”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re also announcing a new handy feature: slide templates. It allows you to get started with Sprites even quicker by letting it generate some visuals (which you can customize, of course) for you when you’re adding a new slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how the “New slide” dialog now looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/slide-template-new.png&quot; alt=&quot;New slide&quot; title=&quot;New slide&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there’s now a new field called “Template” which allows you to pick from the current set of eight template. Once selected, you can immediately test the results and then customize them later during the process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/slide-template-result.png&quot; alt=&quot;Template result&quot; title=&quot;Template result&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about it! As usual, like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to get product updates, hints and tips on creating great-looking visual content!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/11/04/introducing-slide-templates.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/11/04/introducing-slide-templates.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Automatically uploading your video infographics on YouTube</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;automatically-uploading-your-video-infographics-on-youtube&quot;&gt;Automatically uploading your video infographics on YouTube&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello folks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got a new, very handy feature for you today: when exporting your Sprites infographic to a video, you can now enable “Send to YouTube” option which will automatically upload your infographic on YouTube once the export is finished! This makes it so much easier to share and spread great visual stories - definitely a huge win!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s now the “Publish” dialog now looks like when you choose “Create video” option:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/youtube-upload.png&quot; alt=&quot;YouTube publish&quot; title=&quot;YouTube publish&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking “Enabled” next to “Send to YouTube” will bring up a new window where you’ll be kindly asked to give Sprites permission for uploading videos on your behalf. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that your video will be in &lt;strong&gt;“unlisted”&lt;/strong&gt; state in case you’d like to edit its title, description or tags before making it available to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you’ll love the new functionality. As usual, like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to get product updates, hints and tips on creating great-looking visual content!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/10/21/automatically-uploading-your-video-infographics-on-youtube.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/10/21/automatically-uploading-your-video-infographics-on-youtube.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Spread a word about Sprites and get a free subscription!</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;spread-a-word-about-sprites-and-get-a-free-subscription&quot;&gt;Spread a word about Sprites and get a free subscription!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think some of your friends/followers would be interested in trying out Sprites? Well, that’s great, for both you and your peers! We’re kicking off a small referral program which allows you to earn &lt;strong&gt;free 2-month “Pro” subscription&lt;/strong&gt; for spreading a word about Sprites!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/mention-fb.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mentioning Sprites - Facebook&quot; title=&quot;Mentioning Sprites - Facebook&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To claim your free stuff do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mention Sprites in your favorite social network (either by mentioning @spritesapp or by including a link to &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com&quot;&gt;spritesapp.com&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Email us the link to the post as well as your Sprites account details (your name or email address - information you used when you were signing up for Sprites).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We will respond to you with a free 2-moth “Pro” subscription as well as a big “Thank you” letter :-)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/mention-tw.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mentioning Sprites - Twitter&quot; title=&quot;Mentioning Sprites - Twitter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get in touch with us by using our &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt; or by writing directly to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#118;&amp;#111;&amp;#108;&amp;#112;&amp;#097;&amp;#118;&amp;#043;&amp;#115;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&amp;#063;&amp;#083;&amp;#117;&amp;#098;&amp;#106;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#061;&amp;#089;&amp;#111;&amp;#117;&amp;#037;&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#119;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#037;&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#105;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#101;&amp;#100;&amp;#033;&quot;&gt;Pavel&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, our Facebook/Twitter handle is &lt;strong&gt;@spritesapp&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a great, productive week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/10/14/spread-a-word-about-sprites.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/10/14/spread-a-word-about-sprites.html</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>