<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Sprites</title>
        <description>A blog about data visualization.</description>      
        <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://blog.spritesapp.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
            <item>
                <title>New charting options</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;new-charting-options&quot;&gt;New charting options&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people were not that happy with the charting capabilities that Sprites was offering. I’m happy to announce that we’ve substantially improved our charts and I can’t wait to share the details with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;see-it-in-action&quot;&gt;See it in action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to introduce a new feature is to show an example. Take a look at the following demonstration: &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com/view/embed/4673&quot;&gt;New charts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;switching-gears&quot;&gt;Switching gears&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this rather big change what we did first is we replaced &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chartjs.org/&quot;&gt;Chart.js&lt;/a&gt; (a third-party charting library that we used) with &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/chart/interactive/docs/reference&quot;&gt;Google Visualizations&lt;/a&gt;. The main reason for this switch was that Chart.js comes with a very few built-in chart types and also its customization capabilities are quite limited. We didn’t feel like it was a good idea to invest time into improving a library while there’re plenty of alternatives out there (and Google Visualizations is one of the best ones).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that all existing infographics won’t break and will still use Chart.js for rendering all the charts. At the same time all the new infographics will automatically switch to a new charting engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’re several new chart types that are now available to you. Here’s the full list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line chart (was available before)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Area chart (new, separated from Line chart)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bar chart (was available before)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pie/Donut chart (were available before)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bubble chart (new)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tree Map chart (new)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/chart-types.png&quot; alt=&quot;Chart types&quot; title=&quot;Chart types&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, pretty much all the charts are now showing the legend and the X/Y axis with intermediate points (although, it’s possible to show only the chart area) so it should be much easier for the viewers of your infographic to interpret and understand the data. As for the tooltips (small “bubbles” which are typically used to describe a given area/point on a chart), they can easily be added via “Callout” element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/chart-line-callout.png&quot; alt=&quot;Callouts and legend&quot; title=&quot;Callouts and legend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you will like the new charts. If you have any comments/questions/suggestions, feel free to reach out to us at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or via our &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/06/19/new-charting-options.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/06/19/new-charting-options.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Importing data from Microsoft Excel and Google Spreadsheets</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;importing-data-from-microsoft-excel-and-google-spreadsheets&quot;&gt;Importing data from Microsoft Excel and Google Spreadsheets&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re rolling out a new cool feature - an ability to import data for your charts and tables from various third parties such as Microsoft Excel and Google Spreadsheets. Let’s take a look!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re opening a data editor (by clicking under “Data to display” in element properties pane) for “Chart” and “Table” elements, you can see that there’s now a new little button called “Import data” at the bottom right corner of the modal window:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/import-button.png&quot; alt=&quot;Import data&quot; title=&quot;Import data&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When clicked, a new dialog appears allowing you to choose where to import data from. We currently support three options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Excel (.xlsx files) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comma-separated_values&quot;&gt;CSV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Sheets (formely Google Spreadsheets).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Custom URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at each option in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Microsoft Excel” option allows you to upload the XLSX or CSV file from you computer. Once uploaded, you’ll see the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/import-excel.png&quot; alt=&quot;Import from Excel&quot; title=&quot;Import from Excel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Has column names” option allows you to specify whether the first row in the uploaded file contains column headers. The “Has row labels” option indicates whether the first cell in every row contains a text representing a label for a given row. When the file is Microsoft Excel file (and not the CSV file), you can choose from which worksheet to import data (in case there’re multiple worksheets exist).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Google Sheets” option allows you to import data from an arbitrary Google Spreadsheets document. All you need to do is to specify the URL of the document in the text box:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/import-google.png&quot; alt=&quot;Import from Google Spreadsheets&quot; title=&quot;Import from Google Spreadsheets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to remember here: the target Google Spreadsheets document must be published (“File -&amp;gt; Publish to the Web…” option in Google Drive).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last option, “Custom URL”, makes it possible to take any URL and load data from it as long as on the other end there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JSON&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/a&gt; document with the format that can be understood by Sprites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/import-url.png&quot; alt=&quot;Import from URL&quot; title=&quot;Import from URL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all, folks. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/25/importing-data-from-microsoft-excel-and-google-spreadsheets.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/25/importing-data-from-microsoft-excel-and-google-spreadsheets.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Adding rich content using widgets</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;adding-rich-content-using-widgets&quot;&gt;Adding rich content using widgets&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve noticed that people got very curious about one particular building block in Sprites - “Widget”. This is, indeed, the most powerful element which allows you to write arbitrary JavaScript and have it executed when the current slide is being presented to the user. With widgets, you can embed custom graphics (for example, Google Visualizations), display videos (YouTube/Vimeo), show social activity (Twitter cards), load live data and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve put a set of examples for you demonstrating some of the use case: &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com/view/embed/3332&quot;&gt;The power of widgets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to check out the docs as well to see how all the above was implemented: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spritesapp/sprites-sdk/wiki/Adding-rich-content-using-widgets&quot;&gt;Adding rich content using widgets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/22/the-power-of-widgets.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/22/the-power-of-widgets.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Creating your first infographic</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;creating-your-first-infographic&quot;&gt;Creating your first infographic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’re going to go through the process of creating your first infographic with Sprites. We will look at how the editor is structured and what you can do with it. Let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that you see when you navigate to &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com/edit&quot;&gt;spritesapp.com/edit&lt;/a&gt; is the infographic settings modal window:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/tutorial-infographic-settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Infographic settings&quot; title=&quot;Infographic settings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you’re being asked to give your infographic a meaningful title (this is not required, although it’s always good to have one) and choose a theme (a theme defines how the elements on your infographic will look like, what is the background color and so on). You can change these settings at any time without the need of creating a new infographic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the above is done, it’s time to add some content! All infographics in Sprites are composed from one or several &lt;em&gt;slides&lt;/em&gt; (this concept is very similar to how you’d create presentations in PowerPoint or Google Presentations). Every slide, in turn, can have one or more &lt;em&gt;elements&lt;/em&gt; (such as text, charts, tables, figures, etc.) placed on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main menu in Sprites is placed at the left side of the screen. Here’s how the list of slides looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/tutorial-slide-list.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slide list&quot; title=&quot;Slide list&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every slide can have a title and a description (both are optional) and you can re-order slides by just dragging them around with your mouse (slides are being presented in the order they apper in the editor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add a new element, click “Elements” on the main menu and choose the element you’d like to add onto the current slide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/tutorial-element-list.png&quot; alt=&quot;Element list&quot; title=&quot;Element list&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once selected, the element will appear on the slide. Every element has a number of properties your can tweak (for example, a text content for a “Text” element, an image source for an “Image” element, tabular data for “Chart” and so on). To bring up element properties pane, select the element by clicking on it. Once selected, element properties will appear in the left menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/tutorial-element-properties.png&quot; alt=&quot;Element properties&quot; title=&quot;Element properties&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re editing element properties, there’s no “Save” button - you’ll be able to see the changes instantly (these changes are also being saved automatically). When the element is selected (or when the mouse is place over the element), you can see that there’s a &lt;em&gt;context menu&lt;/em&gt; availalbe at the top (sometimes at the bottom):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/tutorial-element-on-canvas.png&quot; alt=&quot;Element context menu&quot; title=&quot;Element context menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Up” and “Down” arrows are used to re-order elements that are stacked (note that the element that is being gragged is not part of any stack). You can also copy the given element by clicking the “Document” icon. The copied element can then be pasted onto any other (or the same) slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re satisfied with your infographic, you probably want to &lt;em&gt;publish&lt;/em&gt; it so other users can view it. The publishing is done by clicking the “Publish” item in the main menu:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/tutorial-publish-settings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Publish settings&quot; title=&quot;Publish settings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a number of settings you can adjust when publising your infographic. For example, you may (or may not) enable player controls so the viewers can navigate through different slides of your infographic manually, if they want to. You may also choose to enabled “Auto play” - this will force the infographic to start presenting the content once it’s loaded. In case you’d like to display a particular slide only (and ignore all others like they’ve never been part of the infographic), you can do so by typing the slide number in “Show only one slide” field. The “Infographic URL” is the publically available URL of your infographic, you can send this to your friends or share it with your network on Facebook or Twitter (there’s also an option to do so right from the editor). Infographics can also be embedded into other pages (for example, you can embed infographic into your blog post), you can read about embedding here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spritesapp/sprites-sdk/wiki/Embedding-infographics&quot;&gt;Embedding infographics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the top right corner there’s a user menu where you can find all your previous infographics and also from where you can access your account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/tutorial-user-menu.png&quot; alt=&quot;User menu&quot; title=&quot;User menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that’s how easy it is to create infographic with Sprites!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/21/creating-your-first-infographic.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/21/creating-your-first-infographic.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>What is Sprites?</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-sprites&quot;&gt;What is Sprites?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a minute to discuss what &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com&quot;&gt;Sprites&lt;/a&gt; actually is, why we started it and what are the goals we’re pursuing with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in a nutshell, Sprites is a free tool for creating great-looking visual presentations on the Web without you needing any design skills. While there’s already a number of existing solutions like Sprites on the market, here’s how we’re different:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) We tried to make Sprites as simple to use as possible without sacrificing the essential functionality. It’s frustrating when your data visualization tool of choice is powerful enough but too complex to use (you could as well just fire up Illustrator instead - at least this one is familiar to more people). On the other hand, it’s equally sad when what you can achieve with the given software is too basic, although the learning curve is short. Sprites takes the good from both ends: it gives you pretty much everything you need to compose great visual stories, plus a bit of additional flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Sprites loves the Web and so everything we do is very Web-focused. For example, Sprites infographic is nothing more than just an HTML page with some CSS and JavaScript applied to it. This makes your infographics more accessible and allows you to easily target broader audience. We also try to leverage all the latest Web technologies in order to improve your visual stories even further. For example, all Sprites infographics come with slick CSS-based animations and are fully scalable with the help from CSS responsive units. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Having a large, vibrant and friendly community is one of the top priorities for us. Good people around can always help you with inspiration and together we can make Sprites so much better! Because of that we put a lot of effort into making Sprites as extensible as possible: already today you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spritesapp/sprites-themes/&quot;&gt;create your own themes&lt;/a&gt; and incorporate custom elements/logic onto your infographic, we’re currently working on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spritesapp/sprites-sdk&quot;&gt;comprehensive JavaScript SDK&lt;/a&gt; which will allow you to customize the behavior and the flow of your visuals even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to sum up all the above and to answer the original question “What is Sprites?”, Sprites is simple (yet powerful), web-based and community-friendly data visualization tool. Try it out at &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com&quot;&gt;spritesapp.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/15/what-is-sprites.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/15/what-is-sprites.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Social sharing, preview mode and other new features</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;social-sharing-preview-mode-and-other-new-features&quot;&gt;Social sharing, preview mode and other new features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a very busy time at Sprites these days - so many great new features are being added and we can’t wait to share the details with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, we’ve added an ability to share infographics on your social networks of choice directly from the editor (available under “Publish” menu item):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/social-sharing.png&quot; alt=&quot;Social sharing&quot; title=&quot;Social sharing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you can now copy any element and then paste it on the same or a different slide. To copy an element use either the “Document” icon under the element context menu or Ctrl+C (Cmd+C on Mac) shortcut when the element is selected. Once the element is copied, the corresponding notification is displayed in the left main menu (to paste an element simply click on an icon):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/paste-element.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paste element&quot; title=&quot;Paste element&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s now become super-easy to preview your work using a “Preview infographic” link located at the top right corner of the screen (next to the user menu):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/preview-infographic.png&quot; alt=&quot;Preview infographic&quot; title=&quot;Preview infographic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great little feature that we’ve implemented allows you to reorder slides by using the drag-and-drop method (the new order is saved automatically):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/reorder-slides.png&quot; alt=&quot;Reoder slides&quot; title=&quot;Reoder slides&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the “Image” element has been substantially improved. Along with the support for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scalable_Vector_Graphics&quot;&gt;SVG&lt;/a&gt;, it’s now possible to select a simple image from the gallery rather than uploading it youself. This mode supports selecting image color as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/image-gallery.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image gallery&quot; title=&quot;Image gallery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was all for now, we hope you liked the new stuff! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/11/social-sharing-preview-mode-and-other-new-features.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/11/social-sharing-preview-mode-and-other-new-features.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Welcome!</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;welcome&quot;&gt;Welcome!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our blog! Here we will be posting information about new and upcoming features, interesting use cases, social events within Sprites and its community and everything else that is related to data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t miss a single bit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;follow us&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;like us&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/01/welcome.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/01/welcome.html</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>