<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Sprites</title>
        <description>A blog about data visualization.</description>      
        <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://blog.spritesapp.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
            <item>
                <title>What is Sprites?</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-sprites&quot;&gt;What is Sprites?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a minute to discuss what &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com&quot;&gt;Sprites&lt;/a&gt; actually is, why we started it and what are the goals we’re pursuing with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in a nutshell, Sprites is a free tool for creating great-looking visual presentations on the Web without you needing any design skills. While there’s already a number of existing solutions like Sprites on the market, here’s how we’re different:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) We tried to make Sprites as simple to use as possible without sacrificing the essential functionality. It’s frustrating when your data visualization tool of choice is powerful enough but too complex to use (you could as well just fire up Illustrator instead - at least this one is familiar to more people). On the other hand, it’s equally sad when what you can achieve with the given software is too basic, although the learning curve is short. Sprites takes the good from both ends: it gives you pretty much everything you need to compose great visual stories, plus a bit of additional flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Sprites loves the Web and so everything we do is very Web-focused. For example, Sprites infographic is nothing more than just an HTML page with some CSS and JavaScript applied to it. This makes your infographics more accessible and allows you to easily target broader audience. We also try to leverage all the latest Web technologies in order to improve your visual stories even further. For example, all Sprites infographics come with slick CSS-based animations and are fully scalable with the help from CSS responsive units. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Having a large, vibrant and friendly community is one of the top priorities for us. Good people around can always help you with inspiration and together we can make Sprites so much better! Because of that we put a lot of effort into making Sprites as extensible as possible: already today you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spritesapp/sprites-themes/&quot;&gt;create your own themes&lt;/a&gt; and incorporate custom elements/logic onto your infographic, we’re currently working on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spritesapp/sprites-sdk&quot;&gt;comprehensive JavaScript SDK&lt;/a&gt; which will allow you to customize the behavior and the flow of your visuals even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to sum up all the above and to answer the original question “What is Sprites?”, Sprites is simple (yet powerful), web-based and community-friendly data visualization tool. Try it out at &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritesapp.com&quot;&gt;spritesapp.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/15/what-is-sprites.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/15/what-is-sprites.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Social sharing, preview mode and other new features.</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;social-sharing-preview-mode-and-other-new-features&quot;&gt;Social sharing, preview mode and other new features.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a very busy time at Sprites these days - so many great new features are being added and we can’t wait to share the details with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, we’ve added an ability to share infographics on your social networks of choice directly from the editor (available under “Publish” menu item):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/social-sharing.png&quot; alt=&quot;Social sharing&quot; title=&quot;Social sharing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you can now copy any element and then paste it on the same or a different slide. To copy an element use either the “Document” icon under the element context menu or Ctrl+C (Cmd+C on Mac) shortcut when the element is selected. Once the element is copied, the corresponding notification is displayed in the left main menu (to paste an element simply click on an icon):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/paste-element.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paste element&quot; title=&quot;Paste element&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s now become super-easy to preview your work using a “Preview infographic” link located at the top right corner of the screen (next to the user menu):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/preview-infographic.png&quot; alt=&quot;Preview infographic&quot; title=&quot;Preview infographic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great little feature that we’ve implemented allows you to reorder slides by using the drag-and-drop method (the new order is saved automatically):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/reorder-slides.png&quot; alt=&quot;Reoder slides&quot; title=&quot;Reoder slides&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the “Image” element has been substantially improved. Along with the support for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scalable_Vector_Graphics&quot;&gt;SVG&lt;/a&gt;, it’s now possible to select a simple image from the gallery rather than uploading it youself. This mode supports selecting image color as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/image-gallery.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image gallery&quot; title=&quot;Image gallery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was all for now, we hope you liked the new stuff! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/11/social-sharing-preview-mode-and-other-new-features.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/11/social-sharing-preview-mode-and-other-new-features.html</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Welcome!</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;welcome&quot;&gt;Welcome!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to our blog! Here we will be posting information about new and upcoming features, interesting use cases, social events within Sprites and its community and everything else that is related to data visualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t miss a single bit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;follow us&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter, &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/spritesapp&quot;&gt;like us&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprites team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/01/welcome.html</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.spritesapp.com/2014/05/01/welcome.html</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>